{
    "author": "Lasang Tamang, refind by Dr Vasile Rus",
    "topic": "For Loops",
    "subTopic": "Using for loops",
    "goalDescription": "Find the sum of natural numbers from 1 to 10.",
    "source": "https://www.programiz.com/java-programming/for-loop",
    "input": "N/A",
    "output": "Sum = 55",
    "code": "public class SumOfNaturalNumber {\n    public static void main(String[] args) {\n\n        int sum = 0;\n        int n = 10;\n\n        for (int i = 1; i <= n; ++i) {\n            sum += i;\n        }\n        System.out.println(\"Sum = \" + sum);\n\n    }\n}\n",
    "blocks": [
        {
            "blockNum": 1,
            "start": 4,
            "end": 5,
            "domainModelQuestion": "What is the goal of the block of code (line 4-line 5)?",
            "logicalStep": "It declares variables to represent a sum and a limit up to which we want to add numbers to compute their `sum.",
            "programModelQuestion": "Can you explain in detail how the goal of the current block of code (line 4-line 5) is actually implemented?",
            "logicalStepDetail": "A variable sum of integer type is declared to hold the sum of natural numbers. Also, another variable n of integer type is declared to represent the limit up to which we want to add numbers to find the sum.",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "questionNum": "1",
                    "question": "Why is variable sum declared and what is its type?",
                    "answer": "A variable sum of integer type is declared to hold the sum of natural numbers."
                },
                {
                    "questionNum": "2",
                    "question": "What does the variable n represent and what is its type?",
                    "answer": "Variable n represents the limit up to which we want to add numbers to find their sum."
                }
            ],
            "statements": []
        },
        {
            "blockNum": 2,
            "start": 7,
            "end": 10,
            "domainModelQuestion": "What is the goal of the block of code (line 7-line 10)?",
            "logicalStep": "It finds the sum of natural numbers from 1 to 10 and prints it.",
            "programModelQuestion": "Can you explain in detail how the goal of the current block of code (line 7-line 10) is actually implemented?",
            "logicalStepDetail": "The value of the variable sum is first initialized to 0. Then, a for loop is used to iterate over all integers from 1 to 10. At each iteration, the current integer i is added to the sum. When the for loop ends, the value of the sum is 55. Finally, the program prints \"sum = 55\".",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "questionNum": "1",
                    "question": "What value is the variable sum initialized to?",
                    "answer": "The value of sum is initialized to 0."
                },
                {
                    "questionNum": "2",
                    "question": "What integer values is the for loop iterating over?",
                    "answer": "The for loop is used to iterate over all integers from 1 to 10."
                },
                {
                    "questionNum": "3",
                    "question": "In each iteration, what happens to variable sum?",
                    "answer": "In each iteration, the value of the current integer in the loop variable i is added to the sum."
                },
                {
                    "questionNum": "4",
                    "question": "What is the value of sum when the for loop completes execution?",
                    "answer": "When the for loop ends, the value of the sum is 55."
                },
                {
                    "questionNum": "5",
                    "question": "What does the program print?",
                    "answer": "the program prints \"sum = 55\"."
                }
            ],
            "statements": [
                {
                    "statementNum": 1,
                    "start": 7,
                    "end": 7,
                    "statementComment": "The for loop below iterates over all numbers from 1 to n. Because n is 10, the loop iterates over all numbers from 1 to 10. The for loop stops executing when i reach 11.",
                    "questions": [
                        {
                            "questionNum": 1,
                            "question": "What numbers does the for loop below iterate over?",
                            "answer": "The for loop below iterates over all numbers from 1 to n."
                        },
                        {
                            "questionNum": 2,
                            "question": "Given that n is 10, in this particular case, what numbers does the for loop iterate over?",
                            "answer": "Because n is 10, the loop iterates over all numbers from 1 to 10."
                        },
                        {
                            "questionNum": 3,
                            "question": "When does the for loop stop executing?",
                            "answer": "The for loop stops executing when i reach 11."
                        }
                    ]
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}